Guide to the Boardman Family Papers
Yale University Library
Manuscripts and Archives
Boardman family papers
1770-1917
MS 89
Boardman family
27 linear feet
Correspondence, diaries, account books, daybooks, legal papers, deeds, and land books of the Boardman family of New Haven and New Milford, Conn., which had extensive real estate holdings in Connecticut and the Western Reserve. Family members include William Whiting Boardman, (1794-1871) lawyer and probate judge of New Haven, Conn.; his father Elijah Boardman, (1760-1823) U.S. Senator from Connecticut who had holdings in the Connecticut Land Company and the three Ohio townships of Palmyra, Boardman, and Medina; his brother, George Sherman Boardman, (1799-1825) and his son, William Jarvis Boardman, (b.1832) attorney for the Valley Railroad Company, and holder of real estate in Cleveland, Ohio, New Haven, Conn., and Chattanooga, Tenn.
Manuscripts and Archives Sterling Memorial Library 128 Wall Street P.O. Box 208240 New Haven, CT 06520 Web: http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/ Email: mssa.assist@yale.edu Phone: (203) 432-1735 Fax: (203) 432-7441
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Murray Crane and Mrs. Frederick A. Keep, 1947.
Description of the Papers
The papers contain correspondence, business papers, account books, deeds, diaries, estate records, journals, letterpress copybooks, notebooks, and miscellanea of the Boardman family of Connecticut and Ohio. The personal lives and professional careers of several generations of the Boardman family are documented. Among the primary figures in the papers are: Elijah Boardman (1760-1823), William Whiting Boardman (1794-1871), and William Jarvis Boardman (1832-1914). Additional individuals represented in the collection include: Daniel Boardman (1757-1853), David Sherman Boardman (1768-1864), Elijah Boardman (1777-1845), Frederic A. Boardman (1820-1890), George Sherman Boardman (1799-1825), Henry Mason Boardman (1797-1846), William Henry Boardman (1862-), Joseph Earl Sheffield (1793-1882), and George St. John Sheffield (1842-1924). The papers document family activities and relationships, extensive land holdings in Ohio, business interests in land and manufacturing operations, the legal careers of William Whiting and William Jarvis Boardman, and the career of U.S. Senator Elijah Boardman.
The Boardman Family Papers are arranged in sixty-six (66) boxes and one folio volume totalling twenty-seven (27) linear feet. The papers are arranged in four series: Arranged in four series: I. Correspondence, 1811-1916; II. Business Correspondence, 1818-1917; III. Miscellaneous Papers, 1798-1865; IV. Personal Papers and Deeds, 1770-1936.
SERIES I, CORRESPONDENCE, 1811-1916, contains letters to various members of the extended Boardman family. General files are arranged alphabetically by author, and include items from many individuals outside the family domain. Eli Baldwin correspondence (box 1, folder 2) consists of letters to Elijah Boardman regarding his land holdings in the Ohio Territory (1811-1829). Letters from Bela B. Clark, Isaac Newton, Rufus Reynolds, and Samuel Swan also comment on the Boardman, Ohio lands of Elijah Boardman.
Other correspondents in this series include: Augustus Henry Mosle, an attorney who handled many routine financial and legal operations for William Jarvis Boardman, members of the Porter, Sheffield, Tyler, and Wright families, and three members of the Schroeder family. Brief notes from Theodore Roosevelt and William Howard Taft, to William Jarvis Boardman, are also arranged in this section.
Select files (boxes 3-7) contain correspondence to and from members of the extended Boardman family. The correspondence is arranged by author in two alphabetical sub-sections. Boxes 3-4 (folders 69-113) contain the first sub-section, and boxes 4-7 (folders 114-176) contain the second sub-section. The correspondence for each author of these letters is arranged alphabetically by the name of the correspondent.
Several female members of the Boardman family are represented in this section. Cornelia Elizabeth Boardman, Lucy Hall Boardman, Mabel Thorp Boardman, Mary Anna Whiting Boardman, and others corresponded regularly with parents, siblings, and a variety of relatives. Much of this correspondence is personal in nature, relating to the health and daily activates of family life. These letters include information on individuals in the New Haven and Mew Milford, Connecticut, area and those family members who travelled to the Ohio area to live and manage landholdings.
The correspondence of Elijah Boardman (1760-1823), (folders 120-126) consists of letters to two sons, Henry Mason and William Whiting. The material focuses on the sons management of family business interests, particularly while Elijah served as United States Senator, 1821-1823. Letters from the Henry Mason Boardman to his father are arranged in folder 147-148. Additional material of Elijah Boardman is arranged in SERIES III, box 45, folders 543-545.
The correspondence of William Whiting Boardman (1764-1871), the eldest son of Elijah and Mary Anna Boardman, includes letters to a sister-in-law, Florence Sheffield Boardman, the daughter of Joseph E. Sheffield, founder of the Sheffield Scientific School at Yale University. William Whiting Boardman was a frequent correspondent of several family members including a Cornelia Elizabeth Boardman, Henry Whiting Boardman, Lucy Hall Boardman, Mary Anna Whiting Boardman, William Jarvis Boardman, Daniel Boardman, David Sherman Boardman, Elijah Boardman, Frederic Alexander Boardman, and Henry Mason Boardman. Letters from Daniel Boardman (1822-1830) and Judge David Sherman Boardman (1822-1855) relate to family finances and land dealings in Connecticut and elsewhere. Frederic Alexander Boardman wrote several letters to William Whiting Boardman from 1837-1856. Early correspondence chronicles Frederic's educational expenses, and requests for support from his uncle, in Waterbury and Hartford. Letters from Boardman, Ohio, detail the estate problems brought about by the death of Frederic's father, Henry Mason Boardman.
Henry Mason Boardman moved with his family to Boardman, Ohio, in 1819, to manage the family lands. In a group of letters Henry wrote to his brother William from 1824-1846, the estensive land holdings and financial operations of the Boardman family are detailed. Frequent sales, leases, and exchanges of property are noted with an exact fiscal accounting of payments and accounts receivable.
William Jarvis Boardman (1832-1915), a Cleveland, Ohio, native who married Florence Sheffield, a daughter of Joseph E. Sheffield is another family member whose correspondence documents the Ohio branch of the Boardman family. SERIES IV contains several letterpress copybooks and other volumes detailing the personal and professional lives of Boardman's immediate family (boxes 48-61, folders 600-645).
Another William Jarvis Boardman (1885-1938), is a primary twentieth century figure in the papers. Much of his correspondence is personal, to aging members of his family. Correspondence to and from members of the Sheffield branch of the Boardman family is also found in SERIES IV, folders 662-679. Letters of Joseph Earl Sheffield (1793-1882) are included here.
SERIES II, BUSINESS CORRESPONDENCE, 1818-1892, contains the bulk of letters relating to the real estate and financial operations of the Boardman family. The sale and lease of land in Ohio is the primary focus of this material. The bulk of the correspondence is with Ohio attorneys, agents, employees, and individuals working on behalf of or with the Boardman family. Correspondence relating to real estate in Tennessee: is also arranged here (folders 190-196) and material from several trading, merchant, banking, and business concerns is also included.
SERIES III, MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS, 1798-1918, consists of notes, financial records and accounts, deeds, copies of wills, leases, and other legal agreements, and other papers relating to several generations of the Boardman family. Much of this material relates directly to SERIES II, BUSINESS CORRESPONDENCE, 1818-1917. Files for 1798 (folders 414-415) include information on the western reserve lands of Connecticut. Dated material for the period 1799-1840 is not extant, but files from 1841-1918 contain a great deal of material on family activity. The bulk of twentieth century material documents the work of William Jarvis Boardman (1885-1938), as the controller of family finances, including the settlement of estates.
SERIES IV, PERSONAL PAPERS AND DEEDS, contains a variety of bound volumes and deeds for members of the Boardman family. This series includes diaries, estate records, letterpress copybooks, account books, notebooks, correspondence, deeds, and other types of material.
Elijah Boardman (1760-1823) estate records and a land book of Ohio real estate holdings, 1799-1858, are among the earliest materials in the series. Elijah George Boardman (1829-1853) and Elijah George Boardman (1868-1900), two Ohio born members of the family, are represented through diaries and, for the latter, letterpress copybooks dating from 1895-1900.
William Jarvis Boardman (1832-1915) files include personal account books, 1860-1914, and material relating to family real estate interests in Ohio and Tennessee. Among the types of material documenting Boardman's professional duties are: claim books, land books, ledgers, and letterpress copybooks (1859-1914). Files relating to the settlement of the estate of Joseph Earl Sheffield (folders 643-645) are also arranged here.
Mabel Thorp Boardman, a prominent figure in the American Red Cross, wrote a manuscript about that organization (folder 596). Files for members of the Sheffield family include correspondence to and from Charles Joseph Sheffield, George Sheffield, George St. John Sheffield, Joseph Earl Sheffield (1793-1882) and others.
Additional papers of the Boardman family are in the possession of Carl Boardman Cobb of Arrora, Ohio. A folder inventory to this material is available, please consult the reference staff.
Arrangement note
Arranged in four series: I. Correspondence, 1811-1916. II. Business Correspondence, 1818-1917. III. Miscellaneous Papers, 1798-1865. IV. Personal Papers and Deeds, 1770-1936.
Access Terms
Adams, Mary L.; Baldwin, Eli, 1777-1841.; Boardman family; Boardman, Amanda Mina Davis.; Boardman, Charles Adolphus, 1788-1880.; Boardman, Cornelia Elizabeth, 1808-1880.; Boardman, David Sherman, 1768-1864.; Boardman, Elijah, 1760-1823.; Boardman, Frederick Alexander, 1820-1890.; Boardman, George Sherman, 1799-1825.; Boardman, Henry Mason, 1797-1846.; Boardman, Henry Whiting, b. 1837.; Boardman, Lucy Hall.; Boardman, Mabel Thorp.; Boardman, Mary Anna Williams.; Boardman, Sarah Hall Benham.; Boardman, William Jarvis, b. 1832.; Boardman, William Jarvis, b. 1885.; Boardman, William Whiting, 1794-1871.; Corey, William.; Crane, Josephine Boardman, 1873-1972.; Graves, John S.; Hay, John Milton, 1841-1905.; Henry, William, 1862-1918.; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1841-1935.; Johnson, Ellen F. Terry.; Keep, Florence Boardman.; Keep, Frederick A.; Kirtland, J. P. (Jared Potter), 1793-1877.; Mosle, Augustus Henry.; Newton, Isaac, 1837-1884.; Phelps, John J.; Phelps, William Walter, 1839-1894.; Pinckney, John T.; Porter, John Addison, 1856-1900.; Porter, Josephine Earl Sheffield, 1834-; Schroeder, Henry Hermann.; Schroeder, John Frederick, 1800-1857.; Sheffield, Joseph Earl, 1793-1882.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; Tyler, Cornelius Boardman.; Tyler, Eliza Margaretta Schroeder, 1906-; Tyler, Mason Whiting, 1840-1907.; Van Buren, Thomas Brodhead, 1824-1888.; Wade, Mary P. Hall.; Wright, Boardman.; Wright, Cornelia E. Schroeder.; Wright, Frederick Amaziah, b. 1871.; Yale University. Students.; Account books.; Building--Estimates.; Business.; Connecticut--Politics and government--1865-1950.; Connecticut.; Deeds.; Diaries.; Family.; Law.; Lawyers.; Middle West.; New Haven (Conn.); Ohio--Industry.; Politicians.; Real estate investment--Connecticut.; Real estate investment--Ohio.; Science.; Southern States.; United States--Politics and government.
Collection Contents
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1811-1916; Series I; 3 linear feet (7 boxes)
  This series contains correspondence arranged in two sections: General and Select. General files are arranged in a single alphabetical sequence. Select files are arranged in two alphabetical sub-sections.
  - General
    - Adams, Mary L., 1890-1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Baldwin, Eli, 1811-1829 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Baldwin, Jesse, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bosley, George, 1890-1891 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Carey, William, 1888, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Clark, Bela B., 1821 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Coit, Henry A., 1886 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Crane, Josephine Porter Boardman, 1884, 1907-1913 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Culmer, H.L.A., 1886 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Doan, G.W., 1821 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Dutton, Samuel A., 1871-1875, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Fox, Marianna Boardman, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Gidding, Hiram, 1822, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Giddings, Jonathan, 1807 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Graves, John S., 1867 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Hawley, H.A., 1878 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Hay, John Milton, 1890-1905 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Ingersall, Jonathan, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Johnson, Ellen F. Terry, 1872-1875 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Keep, Florence Sheffield Boardman, 1881, 1883-1884 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Keep, Frederic A., 1902-1906, no date (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Kirtland, Jared Potter, 1860-1867 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Lyman, Theodore B., 1867-1882 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Mosle, Augustus Henry, 1897-1914 (Box 1, Folder 25-29)
    - Newton, Isaac, 1821-1822 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Pearce, Cornelia E., 1907, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Phelps, Ellen Sheffield, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Phelps, John J., 1894-1910 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Phelps, Sheffield, 1888, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Porter, William Walter, 1868-1888 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Porter, Edward S., 1885 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Porter, John Addison, 1878-1889 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Porter, Josephine Earl Sheffield, 1882, 1890, no date (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Reynolds, Rufus, 1821-1822 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Rouse, Caroline M., 1870 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Schroeder, Caroline Maria Boardman, 1821-1848 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Schroeder, Henry Harrison, 1867-1878 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Schroeder, John Frederic, 1859, 1864, 1872-1895 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Sherman, John, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Stewart, Charles Samuel, 1858-1863 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Swan, Samuel, 1821-1822 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Taft, Helen Herron, no date (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Taft, William Howard, 1905, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Tufer, Cornelius Boardman, 1906-1907 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Tyler, Eliza Margaretta Schroeder, 1860, 1865-1896 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Tyler, Mason Whiting, 1870-1907 (Box 2, Folder 52-57)
    - Tyler, William Seymour, 1906, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Van Buren, Harriette Sheffield, 1881-1889 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Van Buren, Harold Sheffield, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Van Buren, Thomas Brodhead, 1867-1882 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Wade, Mary P. Hall, 1858-1867 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Williams, Jonathan, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Worder, Caroline M. Benham, 1870-1908 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Wright, Boardman, 1901-1914 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Wright, Cornelia Elizabeth Schroeder, 1859-1865, 1874-1911 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Wright, Frederick Amaziah, 1896, 1904, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Wright, George William, 1872-1873 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Select
    - Boardman, Amanda Mina Davis, 18[illegible]2-1900 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Boardman, Augusta Wick (Bissell), 1907 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Boardman, Charles Adolphus, 1839-1856 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Boardman, Cornelia Elizabeth
      - Boardman, Lucy (Hall), 1858-1860 (Box 3, Folder 72)
      - Boardman, William Jarvis, 1861-1880 (Box 3, Folder 73-74)
      - Boardman, William Whiting, 1827-1871 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      - Wright, Cornelia Elizabeth S., 1871 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Boardman, Florence (Sheffield)
      - Boardman, William Jarvis, 1871 1884 (Box 3, Folder 77-78)
    - Boardman, Henry Mason, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Boardman, Henry Whiting
      - Boardman, Cornelia Elizabeth, no date (Box 3, Folder 80)
      - Boardman, William Jarvis, 1859-1899 (Box 3, Folder 81-83)
      - Boardman, William Whiting, 1852-1856 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Boardman, Homer, 1825 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Boardman, Lucy (Hall)
      - Boardman, Cornelia Elizabeth, 1857-1861 (Box 3, Folder 86)
      - Boardman, William Jarvis, 1871-1907 (Box 3, Folder 87)
      - Boardman, William Whiting, 1864-1871 (Box 3, Folder 88)
      - Dutton, Samuel A., 1871 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Boardman, Mabel Thorp
      - Boardman, Florence (Sheffield), 1914 (Box 3, Folder 90)
      - Boardman, William Jarvis, 1877-1914 (Box 3, Folder 91)
      - Moyand, Henri Company, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Boardman, Mary Anna (Whiting), 1827, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 93)
      - Boardman, Mabel Thorp, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 94)
      - Boardman, William Jarvis, 1896-1898 (Box 3, Folder 95)
      - Boardman, William Whiting, [1907], 1909 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Boardman, Samuel W., 1905 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Boardman, Sarah Hall (Benham), 1848-1856 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Boardman, Sarah (Taintor), no date (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Boardman, William C., 1834 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Boardman, William Jarvis (1832-1915)
      - Drafts and copies of letters, 1870-1915 (Box 4, Folder 101-102)
      - Boardman, William Whiting, 1848-1868 (Box 4, Folder 103)
      - Miscellaneous, no date (Box 4, Folder 104-105)
    - Boardman, William Jarvis (1885-1938)
      - Boardman, Florence (Sheffield), no date (Box 4, Folder 106)
      - Boardman, William Jarvis (G.F.), 1902-1914 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Boardman, William Whiting (1794-1871)
      - Boardman, Florence (Sheffield), 1866 (Box 4, Folder 108)
      - Boardman, Frederick A., 1849, 1856 (Box 4, Folder 109)
      - Boardman, Sarah Hall (Benham), 1862 (Box 4, Folder 110)
      - Boardman, William Jarvis, 1856-1871 (Box 4, Folder 111-112)
      - Drafts of letters, 1847, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Boardman, Daniel
      - Pinckney, John T., 1832 (Box 4, Folder 114)
      - Boardman, William Whiting, 1822-1830 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Boardman, Daniel Homer (1803-1834), 1827-1828 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Boardman, David Sherman
      - Boardman, Henry Mason, 1845 (Box 4, Folder 117)
      - Boardman, William Jarvis, 1856 (Box 4, Folder 118)
      - Boardman, William Whiting, 1822-1855 (Box 4, Folder 119)
      - Tomlinson, Daniel, 1831 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Boardman, Elijah (1760-1823)
      - Boardman, Henry Mason, 1819-1822 (Box 4, Folder 120)
      - Boardman, William Whiting, 1820-1822 (Box 4, Folder 121-123)
      - Boardman, William Whiting, 1822 (Box 5, Folder 124-125)
      - Various persons (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Boardman, Elijah 2nd, 1825 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Boardman, Elijah (1777-[1845]), 1830-1836 (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - Boardman, Elijah George (1829-1853), 1847-1852 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Boardman, Elijah George (1868-1900)
      - Boardman, Florence (Sheffield), 1884-1899 (Box 5, Folder 130)
      - Boardman, William Jarvis, 1880-1900 (Box 5, Folder 131)
      - Various persons, 1898-1899 (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Boardman, Frederick Alexander (1820-[1890])
      - Boardman, Henry Whiting, 1860 (Box 5, Folder 133)
      - Boardman, Mason Whiting Tyler, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 134)
      - Boardman, Sarah Hall (Benham), 1851, 1869 (Box 5, Folder 135)
      - Boardman, William Jarvis, 1858-1890 (Box 5, Folder 136-138)
      - Boardman, William Whiting, 1837-1856 (Box 5, Folder 139-141)
    - Boardman, Frederic Alexander (1873-)[1900], 1908 (Box 5, Folder 142)
    - Boardman, Frederick William Henry (1804-1882), 1834-1851 (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - Boardman, George Sherman (1799-1825), 1820-1825 (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - Boardman, G.M., 1841-1842 (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - Boardman, Henry Mason (1797-1846)
      - Boardman, David Sherman, 1835 (Box 5, Folder 146)
      - Boardman, Elijah, 1819-1823 (Box 6, Folder 147-148)
      - Boardman, William Whiting, 1824-1846 (Box 6, Folder 149-159)
      - Schroeder, Caroline Maria Boardman, 1845 (Box 6, Folder 160)
    - Boardman, William Henry (1862-)
      - Boardman, Elijah George, 1899-1900 (Box 7, Folder 161)
      - Boardman, Florence Sheffield, 1877-1916 (Box 7, Folder 162)
      - Boardman, William Jarvis, 1876-1914 (Box 7, Folder 163-176)
- BUSINESS CORRESPONDENCE, 1818-1917; Series II; 9.5 linear feet (23 boxes)
  This series contains material arranged in chronological order.
  - 1818 - 1865 (Box 8, Folder 177-192)
  - 1866 - 1870 (Box 9, Folder 193-202)
  - 1871 - 1872 Jul (Box 10, Folder 203-215)
  - 1872 Aug - 1874 Mar (Box 11, Folder 216-233)
  - 1874 Apr - 1876 (Box 12, Folder 234-252)
  - 1877 - 1880 Sept (Box 13, Folder 253-267)
  - 1880 oct - 1883 (Box 14, Folder 268-299)
  - 1884 - 1886 (Box 15, Folder 281-299)
  - 1887 - 1890 Sept (Box 16, Folder 300-325)
  - 1890 Oct - 1893 Oct (Box 17, Folder 326-342)
  - 1893 Nov - 1895 May (Box 18, Folder 343-358)
  - 1895 Jun - 1897 (Box 19, Folder 359-273)
  - 1898 - 1899 (Box 20, Folder 274-287)
  - 1900 - 1901 Jul (Box 21, Folder 288-299)
  - 1901 Aug - 1902 (Box 22, Folder 300-310)
  - 1903 Jan - 1904 Aug (Box 23, Folder 311-322)
  - 1904 Nov - 1906 Feb (Box 24, Folder 323-332)
  - 1906 Mar - 1907 Sep (Box 25, Folder 333-348)
  - 1907 Oct - 1909 May (Box 26, Folder 349-368)
  - 1909 Jun - 1910 (Box 27, Folder 369-382)
  - 1911 Jan - 1912 Jun (Box 28, Folder 383-393)
  - 1912 Jul - 1914 Jun (Box 29, Folder 394-407)
  - 1914 Jul - 1917 (Box 30, Folder 408-413)
- MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS, 1798-1865; Series III; 6 linear feet (14 boxes)
  This series contains files arranged in chronological order.
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1798-1865 (Box 31, Folder 414-429)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1865-1871 (Box 32, Folder 430-439)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1872-1877 (Box 33, Folder 440-452)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1878-1881 (Box 34, Folder 453-462)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1882-1884 (Box 35, Folder 463-475)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1884-1888 (Box 36, Folder 476-488)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1889-1891 (Box 37, Folder 489-499)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1891-1893 (Box 38, Folder 500-511)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1894-1897 (Box 39, Folder 512-521)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1897-1900 (Box 40, Folder 522-535)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1900-1905 (Box 41, Folder 536-545)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1906-1909 (Box 42, Folder 546-557)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1910-1913 (Box 43, Folder 558-568)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1914-1918, no date (Box 44, Folder 569-581)
- PERSONAL PAPERS AND DEEDS, 1770-1936; Series IV; 22 boxes, 1 folio (10.5')
  This series is arranged in two sections: Personal Papers and Deeds. Personal Papers contains material in alphabetical order. Deeds contains material in chronological order.
  - Personal Papers
    - Boardman, Cornelia Elizabeth: almanac and diary, 1848 (Box 45, Folder 582)
    - Boardman, Elijah: estate records, 1848-1857
      - Estate records, 1848-1857 (Box 45, Folder 583)
      - Land book: Ohio, 1799-1858 (Box 45, Folder 584-585)
    - Boardman, Elijah George (1829-1853): diary, 1852-1853 (Box 45, Folder 586)
    - Boardman, Elijah George (1868-1900)
      - Diary, 1885-1886, 1890, 1899 (Box 45, Folder 587)
      - Letterpress copybooks, 1895-1899 (Box 46, Folder 588-590)
      - Letterpress copybooks, 1899-1900 (Box 47, Folder 591-592)
    - Sheffield, Charles Joseph: estate records
      - 1895-1896 (Box 47, Folder 593)